<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Evangeline M Reynolds</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Evangeline M Reynolds</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From N to Standard Deviation: Visualizing Univariate Statistics</title>
      <link>/post/univariate-statistics-visualizing-variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/univariate-statistics-visualizing-variance/</guid>
      <description>This post goes back and forth between computing statistics for a single variable and visualizing these values. I’m using a subset of the gapminder dataset — European countries in 2007, and focusing on the Life Expectancy variable.
This post is developed from lecture slides for my great students in my intro to data science and statistics course at TU Dresden.
I’m probably most excited about the walk-through of the variance calculation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Games and Athlete Ages</title>
      <link>/post/winter-games-and-athlete-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/winter-games-and-athlete-ages/</guid>
      <description>In February, I made a plot on athletes ages at the Winter Olympics for the data visualization initiative #MakeoverMonday. The initiative is mostly Tableau enthusiasts practicing data visualization techniques. I use it to practice visualization with R. It also serves as a forum for chatting about what works and what doesn’t work in communication data visually which can be good food for thought. My viz had this description:
Winter games individual medalists are most likely to be athletes in their twenties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Layered Presentation of Graphics with &#43;aes() in ggplot2</title>
      <link>/post/layered-presentation-of-graphics-with-aes-in-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/layered-presentation-of-graphics-with-aes-in-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>Here is the post is about how to implement a layered presentation of a graphics. Matthew Blackwell tweeted about the concept earlier this year, which seemed to reasonated with a lot of folks - to the tune of &amp;gt; 1500 likes! Practical, pedegogical stuff tends to get people excited. True for me too.
My best tip on how to give better quantitative presentations is to (a) use more plots and (b) build up your plots on multiple overlays, as in:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blogdown blogpost</title>
      <link>/post/first-blogdown-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-blogdown-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post just a test of blogdown.
It seems to be working fine also with this R code.
x = 5 x^2 ## [1] 25 And this Python code:
print(&amp;quot;hello&amp;quot; + &amp;quot;there&amp;quot;) ## hellothere Let’s check out how a graph looks too:
library(ggplot2) ggplot(mtcars) + aes(mpg, disp, col = as.factor(cyl)) + geom_point() Looks good. I’m very satisfied. Hooray for blogdown!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Hugo and Blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>About Academic Hugo from the creator:
Academic is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. Check out the latest demo of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the Quick Start guide or take a look at the Release Notes.

About Blogdown:
https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/
https://alison.rbind.io/post/up-and-running-with-blogdown/ (very helpful step-by-step instructions)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>