<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Evangeline Reynolds</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evangeline Reynolds</title>
      <link>/authors/evangeline-reynolds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/evangeline-reynolds/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Winters</title>
      <link>/authors/matthew-winters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/matthew-winters/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome.  I am a Visiting Teaching Assistant Professor at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://korbel.du.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;University of Denver&amp;rsquo;s Josef Korbel School of International Studies&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve previously lectured at the Technische Universität Dresden&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://tu-dresden.de/zis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for International Studies&lt;/a&gt; and have consulted on a project with the Violence Prevention Research Program at the University of California Davis.  My PhD is from the University of Illinois, where &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ideals.illinois.edu/bitstream/handle/2142/92939/REYNOLDS-DISSERTATION-2016.pdf?sequence=1&amp;amp;isAllowed=y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my dissertation&lt;/a&gt; won 2018 Burkholder Award for Best Dissertation in the Political Science department of the University of Illinois.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I study effectiveness of international institutions and law especially in the area of security.  More broadly, my areas of study have been International Relations, Methodology, and Comparative Politics with an emphasis on Latin American Politics.  My dissertation focused on compliance with supranational law, using UN Security Council resolutions as my principle case; I conducted dissertation field research in Brazil in the Federal House of Deputies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have extensive experience in data analysis and teaching data science.  I worked as a statistics consultant, at the Applied Technologies of the Arts and Science (ATLAS), at the University of Illinois from 2013-2015. I also served &amp;ldquo;Methods TA&amp;rdquo; in Political Science in the 2015-2016 academic year at the University of Illinois, providing assistance and expertise both to undergraduate and graduate students.  At TU Dresden, in 2018, I  designed and taught a course introducing students to data science tools and statistical analysis for political research.  I primarily teach methodology and data science courses at the Korbel School. Research interests in methodology include communicating uncertainty, visual exposition of statistical concepts and electoral rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been awarded the Fulbright Fellowship (Argentina 2008), Foreign Language and Area Studies Fellowships (2009-2011), Nelle Signor Travel Fellowship (Brazil 2011) and have participated in specialized workshops including the Empirical Implications of Theoretical Models (2010), Public Policy and Nuclear Threats (2013), the Berkeley Institute for Transparency in the Social Sciences (2015) workshops, the Zurich Summer School for Women in Political Methodology (2017), and the Lorentz Workshop: Empirical Research on International Organizations (2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously to my academic career, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked at the U.S. Department of Commerce&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bis.doc.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bureau of Industry and Security&lt;/a&gt; in chemical and biological export controls and have worked in lithium-ion battery failure diagnostics at the Chemical Engineering Division of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anl.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Argonne National Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
